Guide to the Carolyn Sherwin Bailey Non-Book Materials 1946-2008 MS 002
Southern Connecticut State University, Publisher
Carolyn Sherwin Bailey Non-Book Materials1946-2008
MS 002
20 linear feet?
Southern Connecticut State University
Bailey, Carolyn Sherwin, 1875-1961.
Prints, posters, recordings and ephemera.
Provenance
Gift of ?
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
Carolyn Sherwin Bailey (October 25, 1875 – December 23, 1961) was an American children's author. She was born in Hoosick Falls, New York and attended Teachers College, Columbia University, from which she graduated in 1896.[1][2] She contributed to the Ladies' Home Journal and other magazines, and published volumes of stories for children, methods of story telling, methods of teaching children, etc., which include Boys and Girls of Colonial Days (1917); Broad Stripes and Bright Stars (1919); Flint; The Story of a Trail (1922); and Friendly Tales (1923). She wrote For the Children's Hour (1906) in collaboration. In 1947, her book Miss Hickory won the Newbery Medal.
Sources:
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carolyn_Sherwin_Bailey
Scope and Content Note
In addition to the books authored by Bailey, Special Collections holds these non-book items.
Arrangement
Inventory is at item level
Inventory
Access Points
Subject Names:
Bailey, Carolyn Sherwin, 1875-1961.
Subject Organizations:
Southern Connecticut State College
Document Types:
Character dolls.; Posters.; Prints (visual materials).; Photographs.; Typescripts.; Correspondence.
Container List
[The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.]
- Inventory
  - Framed illustration 10 3/16" x 10 ¼". Miss Hickory with an apple. Apparently charcoal, signed in pencil Ruth Gannett. This seems to be the illustration for the title page of Miss Hickory (1946). (Item 1)
  - Composition figure of Miss Hickory with an apple (plastic) mounted in a bell jar, approximately 15 ½" high. Probably based on above illustration. See # 7 below., undated (Item 2)
  - Newbury Medal, 1946. Awarded to Carolyn Sherwin Bailey for the above. Mounted in black leatherette case., undated (Item 3)
  - Print block approximately 6" x 4 ¾" for cover of Carolyn Sherwin Bailey Collection Catalog (Southern Connecticut State College, 1967). According to information on the inside cover this was done by Walter Joseph Washburn under the direction of Dr. Lillian Quirke., undated (Item 4)
  - Miss Hickory doll, approximately 8 ½" high. Head made from a hickory nut, blue checked dress, white apron and collar. Carrying hickory nut basket. Very nearly identical to clothing worn on page 31 of Miss Hickory., undated (Item 5)
  - Scrap Book, 6 ¾" x 8 3/8" First page inscribed "Caro S. Bailey / #638 5th Ave. / Lansingburgh. N.Y." [three lines]. A collection of poetry extracted from newspapers and pasted on pages, with MSS of various poems. Typewritten slip reads "Also her mother's scrapbook of Carolyn's publications." These appear to be very early, mainly 1882 and 1883, but the MS hand appears to be adult., undated (Item 6)
  - Scrapbook, 11 ½" x 16". Consists largely of material relating to Miss Hickory. Largely clippings but some correspondence, including letters regarding #2, above., undated (Item 7)
  - About 25 copies each of Dorothy R. Davis, Carolyn Sherwin Bailey (Hill) (1967) and the Carolyn Sherwin Bailey Historical Collection of Children's Books (1967). (Item 8)
  - Photographs, 15 1/16" x 11 3/8", of a story by Carolyn Sherwin Bailey, "My Lady Chloe," Good Housekeeping, Vol. 49, No. 3 (September, 1909): unpaginated leaves, 232-237., undated (Item 9)
  - Phonograph Recording, 11 7/8" (78 rpm), titled "Miss Hickory." Gloria Chandler Recording, produced by Gloria Chandler, adopted and directed by Betty Girling; Mary Howard Recordings, 37 East 49 Street, New York, N.Y., undated (Item 10)
  - Five printers' proofs of illustrations for Miss Hickory, each 12" x 17"., undated (Item 11)
  - Photographic print of Carolyn Sherwin Bailey (?) as a young woman, approximately 7" x 9 ½"., undated (Item 12)
  - Original art by Dorothy Bayley Morse for The Little Red Schoolhouse by Carolyn Sherwin Bailey (Viking, 1957). (Item 13)
  - Manila folder with artists materials relating to CSB books, page from dedication program?, undated (Item 14)
  - Oil portrait of Carolyn Sherwin Bailey, 12" x 16", "executed in Florence, Italy by Natale Gabici., undated (Item 15)
  - Three "Miss Hickory" type dolls, about 7" high, possibly from the Ozarks., undated (Item 16)
  - One cornhusk doll with pinned label "Mollie" about 8" high, "Southern Appalachian Mountain.", undated (Item 17)
  - Phonograph Recordings (2), 11 7/8" (78 rpm). Titled "The Hobby Horse," a radio program from WMAQ Chicago featuring a reading of Miss Hickory as well as CSB and a group of children who ask questions., undated (Item 18)
  - Phonograph Recordings (2), 11 7/8" (78 rpm). Titled "Carnival of Books" a radio program featuring a reading of CSB's Finnegan II and His Nine Lives (1953). Also a transcript of the program. (Item 19)
  - MSS, 4 pp. apparently in CSB's own hand, entitled: "John Greenleaf Whittier", undated (Item 20)
  - Folded note card [?] with bookplate illustration: "Ex Libris/Eben C. Hill.", undated (Item 21)
  - Day Book marked "G.W.M.CLARK" on cover along with 1949. Typescript pasted to pages "Homemade History" by C.S.B. Several other loose pages. (Item 22)
  - Christmas Letter [?] printed on gold paper, in gold wrap inscribed in ink :"For Marian.", undated (Item 23)
  - Telegram to CSB regarding permission to reprint "Aesop's Fables" in newspaper, together with copy of Hornbook for January/February, 1948, containing the same. (Item 24)
  - Typescript of 11 pages containing genealogy of CSB., undated (Item 25)
  - Stereo card, 4" x 7" of CSB as baby in carriage. Marked: "L. H. Fillmore, Landscape Photographer, Whitehall, N. Y.", undated (Item 26)
  - Photograph of CSB with Boston bulldog in snowscape. 7 ¼" x 5 5/16"., undated (Item 27)
  - Note to a Dr. Hitchcock on a photographic card of house interior., undated (Item 28)
  - Photographic negative of CSB on board ship., undated (Item 29)
  - Three apple labels, 3 ½" x 3 ½", red on white depiction of Miss Hickory with caption: "From Miss Hickory's Orchard.", undated (Item 30)
  - A group similar to #21., undated (Item 31)